<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daminha Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daminha Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:11:45 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Secrets of Cryptography: From Polynomials to Pairings and Commitment Schemes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/d140824/unveiling-the-secrets-of-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:11:45 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/d140824/unveiling-the-secrets-of-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>This blog explores the foundational concepts in cryptography, focusing on the roles of polynomials, pairings, and commitment schemes. It explains how polynomials contribute to data integrity through erasure coding and interpolation, introduces the concept of pairings with their critical properties of bilinearity and non-degeneracy, and guides readers through the setup and importance of polynomial commitment schemes. Building on previous discussions of Zero-Knowledge Proofs, this blog provides an accessible yet comprehensive guide to these essential cryptographic tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Zero Knowledge Proofs: Key Concepts and Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/d060824/understanding-zkps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:58:24 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/d060824/understanding-zkps/</guid>
      <description>This blog explores the fundamentals of Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKPs), an essential concept for understanding security and privacy in ZK-EVM (Zero-Knowledge Ethereum Virtual Machine).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extracting IP Addresses via Chat Apps: Zalo and Telegram</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/d050824/extracting-ip-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 12:46:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/d050824/extracting-ip-address/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I explore how cybercriminals exploit chat applications like Zalo and Telegram to extract users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses through methods like URL spoofing and phishing. By creating and distributing spoofed URLs, attackers can deceive users into revealing sensitive information. I also highlight a specific vulnerability in Telegram that exposes user IP addresses during calls. Learn the mechanics of these attacks, see a detailed proof of concept, and discover essential tips to protect your privacy online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:02:25 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I am Dang Duong Minh Nhat, a passionate mathematics student with a strong interest in cybersecurity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
