<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daminha Blog</title>
    <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daminha Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 13:50:00 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography 6: Can&#39;t predict the next bit? Your PRG is secure!</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 13:50:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p6/</guid>
      <description>This sixth blog in the Cryptography Series explores two fundamental ideas regarding Pseudorandom Generators (PRGs). First, we will learn about the Blum-Micali method, an intelligent sequential construction that allows us to build a PRG capable of extending its output to an arbitrary length from a base PRG that only stretches its input slightly. Next, the post introduces a core security standard: next-bit unpredictability. The highlight of this post is the proof of a classic and surprising result: a PRG is considered secure (indistinguishable from a truly random sequence) if and only if no adversary can efficiently predict its next bit. This provides a solid bridge between statistical theory and practical predictability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography 5: Stream Cipher Vulnerabilities and the Hybrid Argument</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:20:00 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p5/</guid>
      <description>This blog delves into two critical aspects of stream ciphers and pseudorandom generators (PRGs). The first part exposes severe vulnerabilities that arise from the misuse of stream ciphers, focusing on two classic attacks: the &amp;ldquo;two-time pad&amp;rdquo; flaw, where key reuse leads to complete plaintext disclosure, and &amp;ldquo;malleability,&amp;rdquo; which allows an attacker to modify message content undetectably. The second part shifts from attacks to constructions, introducing a method for combining secure PRGs to create a new one with a longer output. The centerpiece of this section is the detailed presentation of the &amp;ldquo;hybrid argument,&amp;rdquo; a fundamental and powerful proof technique widely used in modern cryptography to demonstrate the security of protocols.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography 4: Constructing Secure Stream Ciphers from PRGs</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 12:50:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p4/</guid>
      <description>This post explores the stream cipher, a practical solution to the long-key problem of the One-Time Pad. We delve into how a &amp;ldquo;pseudo-random generator&amp;rdquo; (PRG) can &amp;ldquo;stretch&amp;rdquo; a short key (seed) into a long keystream for encryption. The blog&amp;rsquo;s core focuses on the formal security definition of a PRG—the concept of &amp;ldquo;computational indistinguishability&amp;rdquo;—and presents a detailed proof demonstrating that a secure PRG leads to a semantically secure stream cipher.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography 3: Consequences and Interpretations of Semantic Security</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 16:12:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p3/</guid>
      <description>This blog delves deeper into the meaning and consequences of semantic security, one of the foundational concepts of modern cryptography. We will begin by proving that a semantically secure encryption scheme does not allow an adversary to deduce even the smallest piece of partial information about the original message, such as its parity. Next, through the example of an Internet roulette game, the blog will illustrate how the definition of semantic security is applied to analyze the security of real-world applications. Finally, we will become acquainted with another, equivalent interpretation of semantic security—the bit-guessing game—a powerful and convenient tool commonly used in cryptographic proofs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Process Injection: The Journey to Penetrate Windows&#39; Protected Process Light Security Barrier</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d090725/process-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 16:10:43 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d090725/process-injection/</guid>
      <description>A deep-dive into advanced process injection techniques, demonstrating how to bypass Windows&amp;rsquo; Protected Process Light (PPL) security mechanism. The post covers the journey from classic DLL injection to exploiting the &lt;code&gt;KnownDlls&lt;/code&gt; TOCTOU vulnerability in CSRSS, and finally using Shellcode Reflective DLL Injection (sRDI) to achieve code execution in a PPL process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Session Hijacking: Transferring Chrome Cookies and Bypassing Two-Factor Authentication (2FA)</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d020725/session-hijacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 16:36:42 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d020725/session-hijacking/</guid>
      <description>This blog is a detailed technical guide on how to perform session hijacking by extracting, decrypting, and transferring encrypted Google Chrome cookies from one computer to another. It delves into Chrome’s security mechanisms, explaining how cookies are encrypted using the AES-256-GCM algorithm and how the encryption key is protected by Windows&amp;rsquo; Data Protection API (DPAPI). The blog specifically highlights the complexities involved in handling the newer version 20 (v20) cookies, which are protected by App-Bound Encryption and require SYSTEM-level privileges to decrypt. By following the instructions provided, readers will be able to clone a login session and potentially bypass even two-factor authentication (2FA) mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography 2: Semantic Security Prevents Message Recovery Attacks — A Security Reduction Proof</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 18:47:20 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p2/</guid>
      <description>This blog introduces the notion of message recovery attacks, defines the corresponding security game, and proves that semantic security implies message recovery security via a black-box reduction. A semantic adversary is constructed by wrapping around a message recovery adversary, showing that any success in message recovery would contradict semantic security. This sets the stage for future reductions that interrelate various cryptographic security notions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography 1: Perfect Security and the Limits of Perfect Security</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 23:10:29 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/cryptography/p1/</guid>
      <description>This blog post explores the concept of Perfect Security in cryptography, which guarantees that observing a ciphertext provides no additional information about the original message. We establish a fundamental theorem stating that Perfect Security is equivalent to the statistical independence of ciphertexts and plaintexts. However, Shannon’s Theorem proves that achieving Perfect Security requires the secret key to be at least as long as the message, making practical implementations infeasible beyond small-scale use cases like the One-Time Pad.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding STARK: How to Prove Computation Accuracy Without Revealing the Data</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d091124/decoding-stark/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 12:56:42 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d091124/decoding-stark/</guid>
      <description>In the rapidly evolving world of cryptography, verifying large-degree polynomials efficiently is a challenge. The FRI protocol solves this by enabling the prover to demonstrate that a given polynomial is close to a low-degree one through a series of recursive folding steps. By halving the polynomial&amp;rsquo;s degree progressively, the FRI protocol reduces computational complexity while preserving the security of the verification process. The prover commits to the polynomial&amp;rsquo;s evaluations using Merkle trees, ensuring both integrity and consistency, which are verified through collinearity checks. In this blog, we take a deep dive into the mechanics of the FRI protocol, from the commitment phase where the degree is halved to the query phase where the verifier checks consistency. Whether you are a blockchain enthusiast, cryptography expert, or just curious about the future of digital proofs, understanding the FRI protocol will give you a glimpse into the future of secure, scalable cryptographic verification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Future of Blockchain: Exploring ZK-Rollups and zkEVM</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d231024/unlocking-the-future-of-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 12:16:01 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d231024/unlocking-the-future-of-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>This blog provides a comprehensive overview of zk-Rollups and zkEVMs, highlighting their advantages in scalability, data compression, and enhanced privacy. Despite their potential, challenges such as developer unfriendliness and lack of composability hinder widespread adoption. By examining two primary approaches for building decentralized applications (DApps) on zk-Rollups—application-specific circuits and universal EVM circuits—we shed light on the ongoing evolution of Ethereum technology. Ultimately, the zkEVM represents a significant leap forward, merging familiar smart contract execution with the groundbreaking capabilities of zero-knowledge proofs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding CVE-2021-22659: How to Protect the MicroLogix 1400 from Attacks</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d121024/decoding-cve-2021-22659/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 12:18:15 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d121024/decoding-cve-2021-22659/</guid>
      <description>This blog delves into the vulnerabilities associated with the MicroLogix 1400 PLC, particularly focusing on CVE-2021-22659. Through a detailed analysis, I outline the phases of potential attacks, the underlying Modbus protocol, and the steps necessary for effective remediation. By understanding the intricacies of this vulnerability and employing robust security measures, organizations can better protect their operational technology environments. With the insights gained from the OPSWAT Fellowship Program, this work serves as a crucial resource for enhancing cybersecurity in industrial settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Merkle Trees to Ethereum: A Journey Through Blockchain Technology</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d071024/from-merkel-trees-to-ethereum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 15:11:04 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d071024/from-merkel-trees-to-ethereum/</guid>
      <description>Dive into the fascinating world of blockchain technology with this engaging exploration of its foundational elements! From understanding the robust structure of Merkle trees that underpins data verification to unraveling the complexities of the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM), this blog offers a thorough overview of how decentralized applications and smart contracts operate. Discover how Ethereum revolutionizes trust and security through its unique consensus mechanisms and the role of Ether as its lifeblood. As you embark on this journey, you&amp;rsquo;ll gain insights that not only enhance your understanding of Ethereum but also prepare you for the cutting-edge innovations of zkEVM. Join me as we unlock the potential of blockchain and envision the future of decentralized technologies!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking Cyber Threats: The Art of Phishing with Canarytokens and RTLO Attacks</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d030924/unmasking-cyber-threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 13:49:38 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d030924/unmasking-cyber-threads/</guid>
      <description>In this detailed blog post, we explore the insidious world of phishing attacks carried out via Zalo chat. Through a step-by-step demonstration, we reveal how attackers craft convincing disguised files, use social engineering to lure victims, and employ Canarytokens to track unauthorized access and gather critical data like public IP addresses. Discover the techniques behind this sophisticated form of cyber deception and learn how to protect yourself from falling victim to such attacks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling SNARKs: The Breakthrough Technology in Cryptography</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d240824/unraveling-snarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 12:02:12 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d240824/unraveling-snarks/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, we unravel the complex process of verifying circuit constraints within SNARKs, a cornerstone of modern cryptographic protocols. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how correctness is ensured across inputs, gate computations, and wiring within a circuit, all without compromising the secrecy of the information involved. By understanding these mechanisms, you gain insights into the robust security that underpins technologies like blockchain. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a cryptography enthusiast or a professional in the field, this blog offers a deep dive into the mathematical and logical foundations that make zero-knowledge proofs so powerful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Math Behind the Magic: Exploring Arithmetic Circuits and Their Role in Zero-Knowledge Proofs</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d150824/the-math-behind-the-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 12:49:30 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d150824/the-math-behind-the-magic/</guid>
      <description>This blog delves into the critical role of arithmetic circuits in zero-knowledge proofs, using the game of Sudoku as an analogy to explain complex concepts. From understanding how Sudoku verification relates to the famous P vs NP problem, to exploring the broader implications of arithmetic circuits in cryptographic protocols, the blog offers a clear and engaging overview. Perfect for readers interested in the intersection of computer science, mathematics, and privacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Secrets of Cryptography: From Polynomials to Pairings and Commitment Schemes</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d140824/unveiling-the-secrets-of-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:11:45 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d140824/unveiling-the-secrets-of-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>This blog explores the foundational concepts in cryptography, focusing on the roles of polynomials, pairings, and commitment schemes. It explains how polynomials contribute to data integrity through erasure coding and interpolation, introduces the concept of pairings with their critical properties of bilinearity and non-degeneracy, and guides readers through the setup and importance of polynomial commitment schemes. Building on previous discussions of Zero-Knowledge Proofs, this blog provides an accessible yet comprehensive guide to these essential cryptographic tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Zero Knowledge Proofs: Key Concepts and Applications</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d060824/understanding-zkps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:58:24 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d060824/understanding-zkps/</guid>
      <description>This blog explores the fundamentals of Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKPs), an essential concept for understanding security and privacy in ZK-EVM (Zero-Knowledge Ethereum Virtual Machine).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extracting IP Addresses via Chat Apps: Zalo and Telegram</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d050824/extracting-ip-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 12:46:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/d050824/extracting-ip-address/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I explore how cybercriminals exploit chat applications like Zalo and Telegram to extract users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses through methods like URL spoofing and phishing. By creating and distributing spoofed URLs, attackers can deceive users into revealing sensitive information. I also highlight a specific vulnerability in Telegram that exposes user IP addresses during calls. Learn the mechanics of these attacks, see a detailed proof of concept, and discover essential tips to protect your privacy online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:02:25 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I am Dang Duong Minh Nhat, a passionate mathematics student with a strong interest in cybersecurity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All Blog Posts</title>
      <link>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:02:25 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dangduongminhnhat.github.io/posts/blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
