<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daminha Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daminha Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:11:45 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Blocks of Cryptography: The Role of Polynomials, Pairings, and Arithmetic Circuits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/d140824/building-blocks-of-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:11:45 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/d140824/building-blocks-of-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Polynomials Understanding Polynomials in Cryptography: A Simple Guide Polynomials are more than just mathematical expressions you encounter in school—they are powerful tools with wide-ranging applications, especially in the field of cryptography. But what exactly are polynomials, and why are they so crucial?&#xA;What Are Polynomials? At their core, polynomials are expressions made up of variables like $x$ combined using basic operations: addition, subtraction, and multiplication. Each piece of the expression, known as a term, includes a variable (like $x$) and often a coefficient, which is just a number multiplying the variable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Zero Knowledge Proofs: Key Concepts and Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/d060824/understanding-zkps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 13:58:24 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/d060824/understanding-zkps/</guid>
      <description>This blog explores the fundamentals of Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKPs), an essential concept for understanding security and privacy in ZK-EVM (Zero-Knowledge Ethereum Virtual Machine).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extracting IP Addresses via Chat Apps: Zalo and Telegram</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/d050824/extracting-ip-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 12:46:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/d050824/extracting-ip-address/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I explore how cybercriminals exploit chat applications like Zalo and Telegram to extract users&amp;rsquo; IP addresses through methods like URL spoofing and phishing. By creating and distributing spoofed URLs, attackers can deceive users into revealing sensitive information. I also highlight a specific vulnerability in Telegram that exposes user IP addresses during calls. Learn the mechanics of these attacks, see a detailed proof of concept, and discover essential tips to protect your privacy online.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:02:25 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I am Dang Duong Minh Nhat, a passionate mathematics student with a strong interest in cybersecurity.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
